Gideon Miles Oluku



Email: Milesoluku@gmail.com GitHub: www.github.com/milesuno Portfolio: www.gideonmilesoluku.com

Web developer with experience in agile development. I am passionate about bringing ideas into reality. For example, I have taken the initiative to develop a self-funded project (BarterAnything). I am interested in business automation and creating UX. One of my career goals is to combine my knowledge of business studies and web development.

EXPERIENCE

Front End Developer

InvestCloud (Financial Digital Solutions)

2019 - 2020

Part-time job prototyping, developing, debugging and staging builds for clients and customer-facing User-Interfaces. I attend daily stand-ups, timeline and scoping meetings.

Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript(ES6), React

UX Designer/ Project Manager

BarterAnything (Own Ecommerce Platform) 2017 – 2019

I manage this service during weekends (team of 3). Responsible for: Design, Prototyping, Creating project delivery and timeboxing plans, Hosting Daily stand-up meetings, creating unit and business acceptance tests. URL: https://barteranything.com/

Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript(ES6)

Design: Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, Figma, Balsamiq

Front End Developer Intern

Onfido (Document verification company)

2019

Shadowed across product management, product design, development, business intelligence within the organisation.

Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript(ES6)

Design: Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator

ADDITIONAL SKILLS*

Back End: *Node.js, Express, MongoDB* Methodologies: *Agile, Lean Management,*

Test-Drive-Development

Tools: Trello, Glitch, GitHub, Slack, Git, Postman

EDUCATION

BA Business Studies Degree

University of Northampton 2014 - 2017

International Business, Economics, Marketing.

Computer Science Certificate (CS50)

HavardX 2020 Final Project: *PeakPerformance**, I designed, built and

deployed.

Technologies: C, Python, SQL, JavaScript, CSS, HTML.

Full Stack Developer - Boot Camp

Code Your Future

2018 - 2019

Final Projects: CYFGlossary* and See Your Future - Capgemini*. I was Project Manager and Front-end developer for both projects(teams of 4 and 6), with a focus on UX/UI design and prototyping.

Awards: 'Best Engineered' and 'Most Innovative'

Technologies: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, MongoDB, JSON, RESTful API, HTTP.

Entrepreneurial Programme

The Prince's Trust 2018 - 2019 Business Development, Digital Product Development, Pitching and Negotiating

Agile Project Management - Foundation University of Northampton2017 - 2018

APM: Philosophies, Principles, Practices, Processes and Products.

VOLUNTEERING

Coding Teaching Assistant

Code Your Future

2019 - Present

The class organisation, teaching, event planning at a charity Coding Bootcamp for underprivileged individuals during the weekend.